HIREN PATEL

Senior Full-stack Developer

HI, NICE TO MEET YOU!

I am an experienced full-stack developer with extensive background in high-traffic, API driven, and transactional applications. Throughout my career I've strived to be proficient at all aspects of development - be it creating efficient, cost-effective back-end systems or state of the art, pixel perfect front-end designs. I've led multiple crossfunctional teams at a time in my capacity as a technical lead and senior developer to deliver world-class projects for well-established organisations around the globe.

hieroishere@outlook.com +44 7707 934908

EDUCATION

University of Wolverhampton

September 2008 – May 2012 2.1 in Computer Science (Games Development)

Halesowen College

September 2006 – April 2008 Computing, Applied ICT, Business Studies, and Film Studies.

Holly Hall Academy

September 2001 – May 2006 11 GCSE's including Mathematics, Science, and English.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

PHP Java SQL (multiple variants)
Objective C C++ .NET JavaScript
Node.js jQuery React Angular Vue.js
HTML CSS (Less, Sass, JSS) AWS
SilverStripe (CMS, Framework) WordPress
Craft CMS Kentico CMS Doctrine
Symfony Web Standards
Search Engine Optimization
Software Engineering Database Design
Database Analysis Solution Architecture
MVC Architecutre Quality Assurance
Rapid Prototyping Web Design
UX Design

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Genting Casinos UK

May 2020 - Present

Genting Casinos UK is part of the Genting Group, a global multinational organisation renowned for developing, operating and marketing internationally acclaimed casinos and integrated resorts across the world.

- All-round development and maintenance of the flagship GentingBet online casino website
- Working closely with project managers and designers to make stakeholders vision a reality
- Working closely with QA testers to ensure the most reliable product is made available to our customers
- Prototyping solutions in order to aid the decision-making process
- Analysing and improving existing codebase to create a more robust and efficient application
- Implementing modern web technologies to create the most accessible version of the GentingBet website as possible
- Integrating third-party APIs such as jackpot tickers and live game data to create a more informative experience for our customers
- Understanding and enforcing rules and regulations from the UK Gambling Commission and Malta Gaming Authority

Lead Developer

Made Media Ltd.

September 2012 – May 2020

Made Media is a digital design and strategy agency helping live performance and cultural organisations use technology to connect with their audiences and do better business.

- Technical lead of SilverStripe CMS driven projects
- Management of both internal developers and third-party contractors
- Working closely with clients to explore ideas and requests in order to create bespoke solutions that best serves their patrons
- Implementation of back-end systems including, but not limited to, integration
 of third-party systems, APIs, and payment processors Tessitura, Spektrix,
 Vimeo, Cloudinary, Windcave (formally Payment Express), Worldpay
 (formally Vantiv)
- Developing projects using HTML, JavaScript (vanilla, Angular, Vue.js), and CSS (Less, SASS)
- Architecting efficient, high performant, and highly reliable applications
- Analysing databases and writing advance SQL stored procedures that provides highly customised data based on customer interests and behaviour
- Attending and speaking at StripeCon EU a European community conference dedicated to the SilverStripe Framework & CMS
- Projects including Royal Albert Hall, Wales Millennium Centre, Roundhouse, Center Theatre Group, Los Angeles Philharmonic, New York City Ballet, 92nd Street Y (92Y), Melbourne Theatre Company (MTC), and many others

PROJECTS

GentingBet

https://www.gentingbet.com/

GentingBet is the online casino and sportsbook brand of Genting. It provides premium,

distinctive and socially responsible online gaming experience that draws upon Genting's many years of expertise from around the world.

- Day-to-day operational development
- Liaising with stakeholders to implement innovative new features
- Auditing performance and search engine optimization to improve the quality of the website
- Cross-browser testing and debugging to make sure the website is as widely available as possible
- Integration of iCore online gaming platform
- Integration of games provided by third-party in to the website
- JavaScript React CSS (JSS) PHP Craft CMS Web Standards
 Search Engine Optimization Quality Assurance Rapid Prototyping Web Design
 UX Design

Los Angeles Philharmonic

https://www.laphil.com/

The LA Phil presents an inspiring array of music from all genres at two of L.A.'s iconic venues, Walt Disney Concert Hall and the Hollywood Bowl, to audiences of all ages and economic backgrounds. With the preeminent Los Angeles Philharmonic orchestra at the foundation of its offerings, the LA Phil aims to enrich and transform lives through music, with a robust mix of artistic, education and community programs.

- Lead developer answering directly to project manager and client, and managing a team of front-end and back-end developers
- Attending discovery sessions with the clients to provide a bespoke solution to shortcomings presented by their existing platform
- Review of their existing Django, a Python based CMS, code base in order to port it over to the SilverStripe CMS
- Reverse engineering their existing database in order to automate porting over the Python code base to PHP and PostgreSQL database to MySQL
- One CMS, three websites multi site support to allow the maintenance of three full websites running off a single CMS and database (LA Phil, Hollywood Bowl, The Ford)
- Implementing edit-in-place functionality that allows to content managers to edit content on the front-end without having to open up the CMS
- Implementing a comprehensive block editor to allow drag-and-drop editing of content
- Implementing Google-like categorised search portal to allow customers to easily discover content using the third-party Swiftype service
- Implementing multilingual support for English and Spanish using the thirdparty Weglot service
- Implementing a powerful and well-informed events calendar in JavaScript using custom wrote APIs
- Regular calls with the clients to ensure regular releases of new features goes ahead without any issues
- PHP Python MySQL T-SQL PostgreSQL JavaScript Marionette.js CSS (Sass)
 CloudFront (AWS) EC2 (AWS)

Royal Albert Hall

https://www.royalalberthall.com/

The Royal Albert Hall is the world's most famous stage. Its breath-taking auditorium hosts over 370 shows a year by the world's greatest artists. The magical atmosphere combined with inspired artists creates legendary events.

- Lead developer answering directly to project manager and client, and managing a team of back-end developers
- Implemented the BBC Proms Planner to allow patrons to curate the individual proms they'd like to purchase tickets for in bulk when the tickets go on sale
- Overlooking the yearly launch and on sale of the BBC Proms to ensure all patrons get their desired tickets for the Proms
- Writing highly optimised code that will stay stable with large amount of on sale traffic
- Working with the people from the Hall to ensure the site keeps ticking over
- Liaising with third-party providers and agencies to ensure all of client requests are met to the highest standards
- Integration of third-party digital asset management system (DAMS) to ensure all the clients organisation wide assets are available in one place
- PHP MySQL T-SQL JavaScript jQuery CSS (Less) CloudFront (AWS) EC2 (AWS)
 CloudSearch (AWS) S3 (AWS)

Center Theatre Group

https://www.centertheatregroup.org/

Center Theatre Group, one of the nation's preeminent arts and cultural organizations, is Los Angeles' leading non-profit theatre company, programming seasons at the Mark Taper Forum and Ahmanson Theatre at The Music Center in Downtown Los Angeles, and the Kirk Douglas Theatre in Culver City.

- Lead developer answering directly to project manager and client, and managing a team of front-end and back-end developers
- Integration of Tessitura, a third-party CRM software, that caters to arts and cultural organisations for all their ticketing and admissions, fundraising, and memberships needs
- Integration of both REST and SOAP endpoints to bring the functionality of Tessitura to the web
- Integration of Element Express, a payment processor from Worldpay (formally Vantiv), to allow purchasing of tickets and memberships online
- CMS development and customisations to fit the requirements of the client
- Working collaboratively with the CTG team to produce a website of the highest quality
- Development of modularised Angular components that can be dropped anywhere on the site
- Implementation of a fully integrated purchase path that goes from finding tickets and adding to cart to providing delivery details and checking out
- Writing SQL stored procedures that provides streamlined data for use on the front-end efficiently
- Integration of third-party digital asset management system (DAMS) to ensure all the clients organisation wide assets are available in one place
- PHP MySQL T-SQL JavaScript Angular CSS (Less) CloudFront (AWS)
 EC2 (AWS) S3 (AWS)